Who are you?
你是谁
What is this?
怎么回事
Your Majesty, caught him up in a fishing net. A fishing net.
陛下  我们用渔网捞起了他  渔网
Sire, he's been telling stories. Stories that...
大人  他有许多故事  那些故事...
We believe he's found a...
我们相信他找到了
Ponce de Leon.
庞塞・德莱昂[西班牙探险家]
Says he found Ponce de Leon's ship.
他说他找到了庞塞・德莱昂的船
- Or sailed on it. - No, I told you,
-还乘那船出海过  -不  我告诉过你
Ponce de Leon died 200 years ago.
庞塞・德莱昂死了两百多年了
Aye, but he died searching for something, didn't he?
没错  可他终其一生在寻找什么吧
The Fountain of Youth.
不老泉
How soon can you sail?
你何时能启航
With the tide.
潮起之时
Over here! Lucky heather!
看一看瞧一瞧  幸运草
Pirate swords! Pirate swords!
都来买我的海盗佩剑
Pirate's execution today. Watch him swing!
今日处决海盗  快去看呐
Pirate puppets!
海盗玩偶
Take that, you!
接招吧  小子
Hurry, Papa, or we'll miss the hanging!
快点  爸爸  要不就赶不及看绞刑了
It's not a hanging, dear, it's a trial.
那不是绞刑  宝贝  那是审判
The hanging comes this afternoon.
下午才行刑呢
Pirate hanging today!
今日处决海盗
Come on. Up you get.
快点  起来
Move along, pirate.
快走  海盗
Or should I say, "Captain Pirate"?
是不是该叫你  "海盗船长"
Come on. Come on! Up you go.
快点  快走
Quiet! Order!
安静  肃静
Quiet!
安静
Now appearing before the court,
传唤臭名昭著
the notorious and infamous pirate, pillager,
声名狼藉的海盗  劫掠者
- and highwayman... - Quiet!
-匪徒  -安静
...Captain Jack Sparrow!
杰克・史派罗船长上庭
I told you, the name's Gibbs! Joshamee Gibbs!
我说过了  我叫吉布斯  约什米・吉布斯
- How many times... - Hear ye, hear ye!
-我还要说多少...  -注意
Presiding over these trials,
全体起立  有请主持本次庭审
all rise and attend, the Right Honorable Justice Smith!
尊敬的史密斯法官大人
My dear sir.
大人
Quiet!
安静
Now...
现在
...what do we have here?
是什么情况
Jack?
杰克
Shut up!
闭嘴
I don't recognize him.
我不认识他
Not necessary. You were saying?
没这必要  你刚说什么
Jack Sparrow is not my name.
我不是杰克・史派罗
My name is Joshamee Gibbs.
我是约什米・吉布斯
Is that so?
是吗
- It says Jack Sparrow here. - I told 'em.
-上面写着你是杰克・史派罗  -我说过了
I'm not Jack Sparrow,
我不叫杰克・史派罗
who I would be happy to identify to the court
但我很乐意向庭上指认他
if it would help my case.
要是这能证明我的清白
I think that would be a poor defense,
我认为这辩护并不高明
unless you want to be bludgeoned again like a harp seal.
除非你还想像头蠢海豹一样被打一下
The prisoner claims of being innocent
囚犯辩称自己不是杰克・史派罗
to being Jack Sparrow. How do you find?
你们陪审团以为如何
No trial? But aren't we here to examine the evidence...
没有庭审  可我们是来检验证据...
Foreman, your finding. Guilty?
团长  告诉我你的结论  有罪吗
Guilty verdict means he'll hang.
有罪裁断将处以绞刑
Hang him! String him up!
吊死他  把他吊起来
- Guilty? - That's not fair!
-有罪吧  -这不公平
Shut it.
闭嘴
Joshamee Gibbs, the crime of which you've been found guilty of
约什米・吉布斯  由于你并非杰克・史派罗
is being innocent of being Jack Sparrow.
所以你没有犯下他的罪行
I hereby commute your sentence,
因此本庭赦免你的死刑
and order that you be imprisoned for the remainder
宣判你将被处以徒刑
of your miserable, moribund, mutton-chopped life.
在监狱里度过你那行尸走肉般的悲惨余生
- What?! - Hang him!
-什么  -吊死他
- Hang him! - There.
-吊死他  -闭庭
- Balderdash! - String him up! Hang him high!
-胡说八道  -吊死他  把他吊起来
Means shall be arranged to transport this prisoner
法庭将安排将囚犯押至
to the Tower of London.
伦敦塔
Thanks very much.
非常感谢
Ta.
拜拜
Come on. Get up there.
快点  给我上去
Get up!
上去
Hell's teeth. Now we're both headed for prison.
真见鬼  这下咱们俩都得进去了
Not to worry. I've paid off the driver.
别担心  我买通了车夫
Ten minutes, we'll be outside London Town, horses waiting.
用不了十分钟  咱们就出了伦敦城  有马等着
Tonight, we make the coast.
今晚  我们就能到海边
Then it's just a matter of finding a ship.
再然后就是弄艘船的问题了
- All part of the plan, yes? - Exactly.
-这都计划好了吗  -没错
I arrived in London Town just this morning
我今早刚到伦敦城
to rescue one Joshamee
来救和绞刑架有个约会的
Gibbs from one appointment with the gallows.
名叫约什米・吉布斯的家伙
Seeing as how you're still alive,
鉴于你目前还活得好好的
I'd say it's all been very successful thus far.
我认为目前为止还挺成功
What happened to you, Gibbs?
你怎么了  吉布斯
I thought you were employed elsewhere or otherwise engaged.
我以为你出海了或是在忙别的
Aye. But I always listened
没错  可我一直在
like a thief for news of the Black Pearl.
打探黑珍珠号的消息
Nobody's seen where she might next make port.
谁也不知道她会停靠在何处
Then, I hear a rumor:
后来  我听到流言
Jack Sparrow's in London with a ship and looking for a crew.
杰克・史派罗在伦敦找了条船  在招募水手
- Am not. - But that's what I heard.
-才怪  -可我是这么听说
Fact is, you're signing up men tonight.
说你今晚就在
Pub called The Captain's Daughter.
"船长之女"酒吧招人
- Am not! - Well, I thought it a bit odd,
-才怪  -我是觉得有点奇怪
but then, you've never been the most predictable of sorts.
不过话说回来  你做事总是这么不靠谱
Tell me something.
跟我好好说说
There is another Jack Sparrow out there sullying my good name?
这儿还有个叫杰克・史派罗的家伙冒充我的大名
- An impostor. - Indeed.
-冒名的骗子  -没错
But... an impostor with a ship.
不过  人家有船
And in need of a crew.
还有水手
Which, as fate would have it, so am I.
这些  苍天在上  我也会有
What about you, Jack?
你怎么样  杰克
Last I heard, you were hell-bent to find the Fountain of Youth.
我上回听说  你拼了老命要找那不老泉
Any luck?
运气如何
Circumstances arose and forced a compelling insight
经历了千辛万苦后  我顿悟了
regarding discretion and valor.
此行既需要勇气  也得小心谨慎
- Meaning, you gave up. - I did not.
-那就是说  你放弃了  -我没有
I am just as bent as ever. Hellishly so.
我还是一样不要命  妥妥的
I shall taste those waters, Master Gibbs. Mark my words.
我一定要尝尝那泉水  吉布斯水手长  我把话撂在这儿
Short trip.
真快
All part of the plan, yes?
这也是计划好的吧
No.
不是
You are Jack Sparrow?
你就是杰克・史派罗吗
There should be a "Captain" In there somewhere.
你好像漏了"船长"二字
I've heard of you.
我听过你
And you know who I am.
你一定知道我是谁
Face is familiar. Have I threatened you before?
看起来挺面熟  我是不是恐吓过你
You are in the presence of George Augustus,
在你面前的是乔治・奥古斯都
Duke of Brunswick-Luneburg,
伯伦瑞克-吕纳堡公爵
Archtreasurer and Prince-elector of the Holy Roman Empire,
神圣罗马帝国的首要财务官和选帝侯
King of Great Britain and Ireland, and of you.
大不列颠及爱尔兰的国王  也是你的国王
- Doesn't ring a bell. - I am informed
-还是没想起来  -我听说
you have come to London to procure a crew for your ship.
你来伦敦是为了招募水手
Vicious rumor. Not true.
恶毒的流言  假的
Then you lied to me when you told me you were Jack Sparrow.
那你就是在谎称自己是杰克・史派罗
I am Jack Sparrow, but I'm not here to procure a crew.
我是杰克・史派罗  不过我来不是为了招水手
That is... someone else.
那是...别人
Someone else named Jack Sparrow.
别的叫杰克・史派罗的人
You've brought me the wrong wastrel.
你给我找错了人
Find the proper one and dispose of this impostor.
给我找来本人  把这个冒牌货处理掉
No, wait, wait, wait. Hang on a minute.
不  等等  等会儿
I'm Jack Sparrow, the one and only.
我是杰克・史派罗  独一无二的
And I am in London.
我就在伦敦
To procure a crew.
你要招募水手
To undertake a voyage
进行一场伟大的航行
- to the Fountain... - What?
-目标是那什么泉...  -什么
Will someone please remove these infernal chains?
谁来解开那些见鬼的锁链
Come, come.
来来来
We know you're in possession of a map.
我们知道你有幅地图
So confiscate the map, and to the gallows with him!
那就没收那地图  然后送他上绞架
Have you a map?
你有地图吗
- No. - Where is it?
-没  -那在哪儿
The truth? I lost it.
说实话  我弄丢了
- Quite recently, in fact. - I have a report.
-实际上  就在前不久  -我收到消息
The Spanish have located the Fountain of Youth.
说西班牙人已知道了不老泉的所在
I will not have some melancholy Spanish monarch,
我可不能让可憎的西班牙国王
a Catholic, gain eternal life!
一个天主教徒  获得永生
You do know the way to the Fountain?
你当真知道去不老泉的路
Of course I do. Look at me.
当然  我可是杰克船长
You could guide an expedition.
你能领导我们的远征队
With your permission, your heinie,
如果您允许  大大
you will be providing, then, a ship...
还提供一艘船
...and a crew?
和水手吗
And a captain.
还有船长
Afternoon, sire.
午安  陛下
If I may be so bold, why is that man not in chains?
恕我冒昧  为什么没把那家伙铐起来
He must be manacled at once.
必须立即铐上他
At the center of my palace? Hardly.
在我这宫殿之中  没这必要
Hector.
赫克托
How nice to see a fellow pirate make good of himself.
看到海盗老友从良了真好
Pirate? Nay. Privateer.
海盗  不  是私掠船长
On a sanctioned mission under
为捍卫王上的权威
the authority and protection of the Crown.
而被赋予此项使命
As may be, but first,
就算是吧  不过首先
what has become of my beloved Pearl?
我亲爱的黑珍珠号哪去了
I lost the Pearl as I lost my leg.
我失去了黑珍珠号  正如我这条腿
- Lost the Pearl? - Aye.
-失去了什么意思  -是的
I defended her mightily enough, but she be sunk nonetheless.
我曾奋勇守护她  可她终不能免于沉没
If that ship be sunk properly, you should be sunk with it.
船在人在  船亡人亡
Captain Barbossa, each second we tarry,
巴博萨船长  我们每耽搁一秒钟
the Spanish outdistance us.
西班牙人都会多甩开我们一点
I have every confidence you will prevail and be rewarded
我非常相信  以你的热忱
with the high station you so desire.
你必将无往不胜  赢得我的奖赏
- To serve doth suffice, sire. - You, sir, have stooped.
-愿尽绵薄之力  陛下  -你也太不要脸了
Jack, our sands be all but run.
杰克  咱俩的日子还长着呢
Where's the harm in joining the winning side?
识时务  方能成俊杰
And you do meet a nicer class of person.
而你面前的我确实更有地位了
I understand everything.
这我都能理解
Except that wig.
除了你那假发
He's getting away! Stop him!
他要逃走了  抓住他
- Head him off! - No! Stop that pirate!
-拦住他  -不  拦住那个海盗
Come down!
下来
- He escaped? - Leave it to me, sire.
-他逃走了  -交给我吧  陛下
Guards! Guards!
卫兵  卫兵
- Arms at ready! - Aye, sir!
-准备好武器  -遵命  大人
Find him!
找到他
Finders keepers!
捡着就是我的
There!
在那儿
Is that it?
这就完事了
Halt! Stop that carriage!
停下  拦下那辆马车
Head him off!
截住他
Out of the way!
让开
Stop that pirate!
抓住那个海盗
Move out of the way!
都让开
Stop that man!
抓住那个人
Don't let him get away!
别让他跑了
Fire!
开火
He's getting away! After him! Stop him!
他跑了  追上他  抓住他
After him!
追上他
Filthy pirate.
下贱的海盗
Hello, Jackie.
你好  小杰
Hello, Dad.
你好  老爸
I heard you're putting together a crew.
我听说你在招募水手
If enough people keep saying it, it must be true.
流言传了一千遍  也就成了真
I heard where you're headed. The Fountain.
我知道你要去哪  不老泉
Have you been there?
你去过吗
Does this face look like it's been to the Fountain of Youth?
你看我这张脸  像是去过不老泉的样子吗
- Depends on the light. - Son, the Fountain.
-光线问题  -儿子  不老泉
There'll be items required for the profane ritual.
需要一些特殊道具完成仪式
Two chalices.
两只圣杯
- On the map there was a chalice. - Two, silver.
-地图上是有个圣杯  -两只  银制的
From the Ponce de Leon ship. You'll need both.
在庞塞・德莱昂的船上  你需要两只
- For? - The ritual. Don't be a fool, Jackie.
-为什么  -完成仪式  别傻了  小杰
Find out every detail before you set sail.
做好完全的准备  再起航
Oh, set sail. Love to.
启航  那很好
But for that, I may need a ship.
可我得有艘船才行
Those folk, over there, they have a ship.
那边的那些家伙  他们有船
They're signing up sailors right now.
他们现在就在招水手
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
And one last thing, Jackie.
最后一件事  小杰
The Fountain will test you. Mark my words.
不老泉会考验你  记住我的话
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
There is nothing can console me
只有快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
能让我的心得到慰藉
I hear you be recruiting a crew.
我听说你们在招水手
Aye. That is,
是的
Jack Sparrow be putting together a modest venture.
杰克・史派罗正在准备一场探险
You got some nerve, ain't ya?
你有点神经兮兮的呀
Turning up here dressed like that?
穿成这副模样
What are you, some kind of impostor?
你算哪根葱  冒名顶替的吗
Have you any idea who I am, mate?
你知道我是谁吗  朋友
Oi, muckers!
喂  哥儿几个
There's a bloke here what's forgotten his own name!
这儿有个哥们连自己是谁都想不起来
Lads, I'm sailing with Sparrow.
大伙儿  我要和史派罗一起出海了
Who'll buy a sailor a drink?
谁来给水手买杯酒喝
Who's next?
下一位
Bring us some more of those ones.
再来一点
Yeah, make it four.
对  再来四个
You've stolen me, and I'm here to take meself back.
你偷了我的身份  我来要回我自己
Stop doing that.
别学我
Only one person alive knows that move.
只有一个人会那招
Always wanted to do that.
早就想这么干了
Hello, Angelica.
你好  安琪莉卡
Hello, Jack. Are you impressed?
你好  杰克  没想到吧
I think I almost killed you once or twice there.
我想有那么一两次  我差点就能杀了你
I'm touched at this most sincerest form of flattery.
你这真挚的赞扬让我分外感动
But why?
可这是为什么
You were the only pirate I thought I would pass for.
你是唯一一个我能装得像的海盗
That is not a compliment.
这可不是什么好话
Don't worry, Jack. I forgave you a long time ago.
别担心  杰克  我早就原谅你了
- For what? For leaving you? - Recall that I left you.
-原谅什么  我甩了你  -好好想想  是我甩的你
A gentleman allows a lady to maintain her fictions.
绅士总得纵容女士沉溺在她的小幻想中
Look, Sparrow. As long as my sailors get their money,
听着  史派罗  只要我的水手有钱可赚
they're willing to put up with any number of peculiarities.
不管是什么样的事情  他们都能凑合
There is one peculiarity with which I will not put up with.
有那么一件事情  我可凑合不了
I will be impersonated as "Captain." Nothing less.
我来演船长  必须这样
Well, for that, you need a ship,
要想当船长  你得先有艘船
and as it turns out, I have one.
而我  恰恰就有一艘
I could use a ship.
我正好需要一艘船
I hear tell you've been to the Fountain.
我听说你去过那里
There be a lot of hear-telling going on these days.
最近小道消息真不少
- The Fountain of Youth.  - Dearest Angelica, fret not.
-不老泉  -亲爱的安琪莉卡  别担心
You still have a few usable years left.
你还年轻
Always so charming.
真会讲话
You didn't answer me.
你没回答我
Aye. Regarding the Fountain. Waste of time, really...
哦对  至于不老泉  那是浪费时间  真的...
Milady, I see unseamanlike
夫人  发现一群可疑的人
fellows of an officious-looking nature.
不像船员  像是来找茬儿的
Wretched pirates! Find 'em! Maggots!
无耻的海盗  抓住他们  这帮无赖
Friends of yours?
你的朋友吗
I may have unintentionally slighted some king or other.
我可能不小心惹火了国王之类的人
Open it!
打开
- Yeah, you haven't changed.  - Implying the need?
-你还是没变  -能给点提示吗
Yes.
那好
Open this door, in the name of His Majesty.
打开门  这是国王的命令
You betrayed me. You seduced me and you used me.
你背叛了我  还引诱和利用我
I was innocent of the ways of men.
骗术什么的我本来并不擅长
You demonstrated a lot of
就一个我要带坏的人来说
technique for someone I supposedly corrupted.
你有点过于强大了
Imminent danger. Here, now, milady!
太危险了  快点  夫人
Open it!
打开
I was ready to take my vows. And you...
我正要宣誓  你却...
What were you doing in a Spanish convent, anyway?
你究竟怎么会出现在西班牙的女修道院
Mistook it for a brothel. Honest mistake.
把那当妓院了  纯属失误
- There he is!  - Over there!
-他在那  -那边
We are at a disadvantage.
我们的处境很被动
Speak for yourself. Unlike some who pretend to be,
那是你  我可不像某人装成别人
but cannot, in fact, hold a candle to,
实际上连人家一根毛都及不上
I am Captain Jack Sparrow.
我才是杰克・史派罗船长
How can you say I used you?
你怎么能说我利用你
You know exactly how.
你明明知道
I know, but how can you say it?
我知道  但你怎么能说出口
- So, what is it?  - What is what?
-那到底是什么  -什么是什么
About the Fountain.
不老泉
What do you know?
你知道什么
You don't happen to be in possession
庞塞・德莱昂的两个圣杯
of two silver chalices, circa Ponce de Leon?
不会就刚好在你这吧
- No.  - Thought not.
-没有  -我想也是
- Why?  - I hear stories.
-怎么  -我听到有些说法
Rumors.
传言
You are, of course, aware of the ritual.
你肯定知道仪式吧
Yes, I am.
是的
What is it? What is required?
是什么样的  需要什么道具
A mermaid, Jack.
一条美人鱼  杰克
There's been a mistake.
一定是搞错了
It's a life sentence, not death. Life!
我是被判无期徒刑  不是死刑
- Barbossa.  - Thank you, gentlemen.
-巴博萨  -谢谢  先生们
I trust you can tie a noose.
我相信你会系绳索
That's a hard thing,
这是强人所难
forcing a man to twist his own hanging rope.
让人给自己绑绞绳
You must lie in your bed the way you made it.
这叫自作自受
What's happened to you?
你们俩怎么了
- Where be Jack Sparrow?  - He escaped.
-杰克・史派罗呢  -他跑了
I'm on a tight schedule, Gibbs.
我很赶时间  吉布斯
The HMS Providence sets sail at first light.
皇家海军明晨就要出发
If you do not care to watch it hanging here dead,
如果你不想死后满嘴苍蝇
with a mouth full of flies...
还被挂在这里示众
...speak now.
就赶快招了
Take me with you. Any point of the compass...
带上我  罗盘上的所有地点...
Take you where, Gibbs? The Fountain? Aye?
带你去哪  吉布斯  不老泉吗
Is that where Jack be headed?
杰克也要去那儿吗
Have you anything you can offer me, Gibbs?
你能给我什么  吉布斯
Anything at all?
有吗
Upon me naked word, you'll not see the dawn.
说白了  你见不到黎明了
Hand it over.
把它给我
- You fool!  - I had just enough time
-你个蠢货  -我有足够时间
to study those infernal circles.
好好研究了下那张地图
Every route, every destination. All safe... in here.
所有路线和目的地  全都牢牢记在这了
Welcome back to His Majesty's navy, Master Gibbs.
欢迎回到皇家海军  吉布斯水手长
Show a leg, sailor!
起床  水手
Aye, sir.
遵命  长官
What?
啥
- There's been a horrible mistake.  - Keep moving.
-这是个天大的误会  -继续走
- I'm not supposed to be here.  - Many a man's woken up at sea,
-我不该在这  -许多人在海上醒来
no idea what, when, wherefore or why.
大脑一片空白
No memory of the night afore, whence he signed up
完全不记得前天晚上是在哪签的协议
and drank away all his bonus money.
又是在哪把佣金全部买了酒喝
No, no, no. You don't understand, mate.
不  不  不  你不明白  伙计
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow. The original. The only.
我是杰克・史派罗船长  如假包换  独一无二
Scrum, and the pleasure's all mine. Now, keep moving.
我叫史考姆  很高兴认识你  好了  走吧
Scrum.
史考姆
Get your elbows in!
过来
Why is there a glass coffin?
这怎么有一口玻璃棺材
Do I look like a man in charge?
我看起来像是管事儿的吗
- Where am I?   - 'Scuse me, Captain Sparrow, sir.
-这是哪儿  -不好意思  史派罗船长
I be right honored to welcome you aboard
我很荣幸地欢迎您登上这艘
our world-renowned vessel of infamy, Queen Anne's Revenge.
臭名昭著的安娜王后复仇号
Blackbeard.
黑胡子
Work!
干活儿
- He's a curious one.  - He's been zombiefied.
-这人挺古怪  -他是还魂尸
Zombiefied.
还魂尸
Blackbeard's doing. All the officers are the same.
黑胡子干的  管事儿的都是
Makes 'em more compliant.
这样的人更服从命令
And perpetually ill-tempered.
还有没完没了的坏脾气
- Come on. Scrub.  - Yeah.
-快擦  -好
Pull! Pull! Pull!
拉  拉  拉
Five days underway, at least.
我们航行了至少五天
Aye. You can tell that by the smell of the sea?
是啊  你是根据海的味道辨别的吗
Smell of the crew.
船员的味道
Oi. What did that poor sod do?
那个可怜鬼做了什么
And how can I make sure to not?
我怎么保证不重蹈覆辙
Him? Churchly fellow.
他吗  是个牧师
Always going on about the Lord Almighty.
总是宣扬上帝万能
Bible-thumper on this ship?
船上还有讲《圣经》的牧师
A missionary is his story.
用他的话说是传教士
What I heard was he got captured in a raid.
我听说他在一次突袭中被逮住
Rest of the ship got killed, but not 'im.
船上其他人都死了  除了他
First mate wouldn't let it happen
因为他的虔诚信仰
on account of his premier standing with the Lord.
大副放过了他
A first mate sticking her neck out for some prisoner.
大副她为了这人冒了很大风险
That you don't see.
你能想到吗
"Her"? First mate is a "Her"?
她?  大副是女的?
Back to work!
回去干活儿
Steady as she goes.
船速很稳定
You are a ruthless, soulless, cross-grained cur.
你个残忍  没良心  遭报应的卑鄙小人
- I told you I had a ship.  - No, Blackbeard has a ship,
-我跟你说过我有条船  -不对  是黑胡子的船
upon which I am now imprisoned.
而我就被囚禁在这条船上
We can do this, Jack.
我们可以联手  杰克
The Fountain of Youth, like you always wanted.
不老泉  你一直都想去
Blackbeard. Edward Teach. The pirate all pirates fear.
黑胡子  爱德华・提奇  所有海盗都惧怕的海盗
Resurrector of the dead in his spare time.
没事儿喜欢给尸体还魂
- He will listen to me.  - He listens to no one.
-他会听我的话  -他不听任何人
Maybe to his own daughter?
连他女儿也不听吗
Daughter as in... beget by?
女儿  亲生的吗
Long-lost. Recently found.
多年失散  最近团聚
Who loves her dear papa with all her soul.
她全心全意爱着她的父亲
- He bought that?  - I sold that.
-他居然信了  -凭我的三寸不烂之舌
Then it's the Fountain of Youth for him,
那么想去不老泉的是他
or him and you, not you and me.
或者你和他  但不是你和我
No, Jack, that's the best part.
错了  杰克  最妙的来了
He will be dead.
他会死
You'll be handling that part yourself, then?
那你就能独吞了
There is a prophecy.
有个预言
Maybe you don't believe in the supernatural.
或许你不相信神奇力量
Oh, no, no. I've seen a thing or two.
不  不  不  我也见过几次
The prophecy is this:
预言就是
Blackbeard will meet his death within a fortnight
黑胡子在两星期内
at the hands of a one-legged man.
会死于一个独腿男人手中
That's why he needs the Fountain, Jack.
所以他要找不老泉  杰克
Master Gibbs, short we are a map.
吉布斯水手长  我们少张海图
Perhaps you'd be so kind as to provide us an heading.
或许你该给我们指个方向
Be a gem and pour me a gulper.
你能行行好  给我来点酒吗
Nay. We be privateers, not pirates, Master Gibbs.
不  我们不是海盗  这是条私掠船  吉布斯水手长
And in the king's name, we behave as such.
看在国王的名义上  我们就得这样
Aye, Captain.
是  船长
Be we on the proper course, Gibbs?
我们的航线对吗  吉布斯
Aye, it be proper. There's your proof.
没错  不信看那边
The Spaniard.
西班牙人
All hands! Battle stations! Get to windward!
全体船员  到战斗岗位  到上风向
- All hands, windward!  - Harden up two points!
-全体船员  上风向  -帆向上拉紧两个点
- Two points!  - Cast loose the cannons!
-两个点  -解开炮索
- Gunners, take posts!  - Take position! Gunners ready, sir!
-炮手就位  -就位  炮手准备完毕 船长
- Out! Thrust!  - Await orders.
-准备发射  -待命
Steady!
稳住
Guns armed, awaiting orders, sir.
大炮准备完毕  等待指示  船长
Sir. Orders, sir?
船长  下命令吗  船长
He never so much as turned his head.
他根本没在意我们
The Fountain is the prize.
不老泉才是目标
It appears we be not even worth the time it'd take to sink us.
看来他们不屑于袭击我们
And now we've fallen behind. All hands, make more sail!
现在我们落后了  全员  快速前进
All hands, more sail!
全员  加速前进
Ride hard between wind and tide!
加速前进  迎着风浪向前
The topic, gentlemen, is mutiny.
先生们  我们的话题是  夺权
Mutiny most foul.
叛乱
Aye. I signed up to sail under Jack Sparrow, not some pretender.
没错  我是要为杰克・史派罗效力  不是什么冒牌货
And a lady, at that.
更何况还是个女人
And mention was failed to be made of this uncanny crew.
还不知道船上都是些可怕的神奇生物
Make my toes curl, they do.
他们弄弯了我的脚趾
I got 'em. All of them.
所有的我都弄来了
- Well done.  - Good lad.
-干得好  -好小子
On to it, then. Blackbeard.
还有一点  黑胡子
- What are his habits?  - Stays mostly to his cabin.
-他有什么习惯  -大多待在他房间里
That's right, mostly to his cabin.
是的  基本不出来
- Yes, but when he comes out...  - He don't really come out.
-对  但他一旦出来  -他没出来过
He must come out sometime.
他肯定会出来
Not really, no.
从没露面过  没有
Any of you sail with him before?
你们中有谁和他出过海吗
- No, no.  - I've never.
-没有  没有  -从来没有
Definitely not.
绝对没有
- Any of you seen him before?  - Not really, no.
-你们有人见过他吗  -没有
Stays to his cabin, no one sailed with him,
他待在房间里  没人和他出过海
no one's seen him...
没人见过他
Good news, gentlemen. This is not Blackbeard's ship.
好消息  先生们  这不是黑胡子的船
This is not the Queen Anne's Revenge.
这不是安娜王后复仇号
No, this be the Queen Anne's Revenge, right enough.
不  这是安娜王后复仇号  千真万确
How do you know?
你怎么知道
I've seen the name, on the back of the ship.
我见过船尾的船名
Gentlemen, sirs, fellow conscriptees...
先生们  我的难兄难弟们
...you have been monstrously deceived.
你们被彻头彻尾地骗了
- We are decepted, then?  - Yes.
-我们被骗了  -是的
You've nay been informed of a destination.
他们从没告诉过你们目的地
Death lies before us
死亡正等着我们
as we sail for the Fountain of Youth.
因为我们要开往不老泉
It would be a sorry plight, mates.
这下我们就惨了  兄弟们
- Death, for certain.  - The garden of darkened souls.
-死亡  毫无疑问  -那里是恶灵的殿堂
- Untimely our ends will be.  - Unless...
-我们活不了多久了  -除非
...we take the ship.
我们要占领这条船
We take the ship, then. Now!
那就这么干吧  就现在
Go on, then.
去啊
- Help me, shipmates!  - Give it to 'em!
-来帮忙  水手们  -给他们
- Wake up! It's ours!  - Come on!
-醒醒  船是我们的了  -来吧
Get up! Off your backside!
起来  起来
- Get off your fannies!  - Take it to them, lads!
-别黏糊了  -分给他们  小子
Help me! Fight!
帮我  反抗
Jack.
杰克
If this is a dream, you can keep the sword and boots on.
如果我在做梦  你带着剑穿着靴子也无妨
- If it's not...  - It's a dream.
-如果不是  -你在做梦
No, it's not!
不  不是
I thought I should give you fair warning, we're taking the ship.
我想我该提醒你下  我们要占领这艘船
Nothing personal.
不是针对你
Think you might be better off if you just...
我觉得这样对你有好处
...stay out of it.
如果你能别管这事的话
Boggit.
丑八怪
Wretch!
混蛋
You're either with us or against us!
你是敌是友
I am not with you, neither am I against you!
非敌非友
Can he do that?
这不是自相矛盾吗
He's religious. I believe it's required.
他信教  信教的人都这样
Fight to the bitter end, you cack-handed deck apes!
受死吧  你们这帮笨头笨脑的蠢货
Take him, men. Tie him down tight!
抓住他  弟兄们  绑紧他
The ship is ours!
船是我们的了
Gentlemen.
先生们
I be placed in a bewilderment.
你们让我很困惑
There I were, resting,
我正在里面休息
and upon a sudden, I hear an ungodly row on deck.
突然听到甲板上传来不和谐的吵闹声
Sailors abandon their posts
水手们擅离职守
without orders, without leave.
无故缺勤
Men before the mast,
桅杆前的兄弟
taking the ship for themselves.
想把船据为己有
What be that, First Mate?
怎么回事  大副
- Mutiny, Captain.  - Again?
-有人叛乱  船长  -什么
- Mutiny!  - Aye.
-叛乱  -明白了
Mutiny.
叛乱
And what fate befalls mutineers?
那叛乱者的下场是什么
Now, we know the answer to that, do we not?
我们知道该怎么做吧
Mutineers hang!
把叛乱者都吊起来
Captain, I wish to report a mutiny.
船长  我想举报一场叛乱
I can name fingers and point names.
我能指名道姓
No need, Mr. Sparrow.
不需要  史派罗先生
They are sheep. You, their shepherd.
他们是羊群  而你  是牧羊人
Have I mentioned, sir, what a lovely daughter you have?
我有说过吗  船长  你女儿是个美女
A fitting last sight for a doomed soul.
你小子死前还挺有眼福
Remember, Father. We need him.
等等  父亲  我们需要他
If I don't kill a man every now and then,
如果我不时常杀个人
- they forget who I am.  - Coward!
-他们会忘了我是谁  -懦夫
They do not forget.
他们不会忘
Your crew sees you for the miscreant you are.
你的船员们把你看做恶魔
A coward, no matter how many you slay.
无论你杀多少人  你都是个懦夫
Twice in one day, I find myself in a bewilderment.
一天之中  我两次感到困惑
You are not bewildered, you are afraid.
你不是困惑  你是恐惧
You dare not walk the
你不敢走正义之路
path of righteousness, the way of the light.
光明之路
No, sir. The truth is it be much simpler than all that.
不  牧师  事实比这简单得多
- I am a bad man.  - That, too.
-我就是个坏人  -没错
I might have to kill you too, catechist.
我也能杀了你  传教士
- No!  - All Latin blood like her mother.
-不  -就跟她老妈一个样
Father, I beg you.
父亲  我求求你
There I be again, forgetting why the missionary is here.
我又忘了这传教士为什么还活着了
My daughter fears for my soul, or what's left of it.
我女儿担心我的灵魂  或是我剩下的灵魂
You truly wish to save me, my child?
你真想救赎我吗  孩子
Every soul can be saved.
所有灵魂都能被救赎
Be that true, young cleric?
真的吗  年轻的牧师
Yes. Though you I see as a bit of a long shot.
是的  虽然我觉得你的希望渺茫
Still, I pray for every
不过  我仍然为
unfortunate soul on this hell-bound vessel.
这艘地狱之船上所有不幸的灵魂祈祷
You disarm me with your faith.
你的信念让我放下武器
Eight bells!
八击钟
Which of you unfortunate souls stood watch?
刚才是哪个倒霉鬼在放哨
- I did. I stood watch. - Gunner.
-是我  我在放哨  -炮手
You?
你
Aye.
是的
The cook.
厨子
Perfect. Lower the longboat!
非常好  放下大艇
Bring her about!
亮出大炮
Why do you do this?
为什么要这样
Mutiny. Our laws be clear.
这是叛变  规矩必须遵守
Our laws allow the Captain to show leniency.
规矩允许船长网开一面
I have given this man a chance to determine his fate,
我给了他决定自己命运的机会
a gift not afforded to all.
这可不是人人都能有的
Oh, you now.
喂  你
Chance to show the worth of your prayers.
现在来瞧瞧你的祈祷有没有用
Pray he be delivered from... evil?
祈祷他从魔鬼手中得到...拯救
Course made!
发射
Stop. Give that man a chance. Give yourself a...
住手  给他个机会  给你自己...
You know when I feel closest to our Maker?
知道我什么时候觉得最接近造物主吗
When I see suffering, pain and anguish.
当我看到苦难  伤痛和苦恼
That's when the true design of this world is revealed.
世界的真实面貌就会显现
And I see it revealed when in times of hardship and tragedy,
当苦难和悲剧发生之时
kindness and compassion are shown to those in need.
需要的人会得到善意和同情
Perhaps you should pray for him to be unharmed, yes?
也许你该祈祷他不受伤害  对吧
- Please, there's still hope... - Again!
-求求你  还有希望  -再来一次
I actually have no interest in the Fountain whatsoever,
其实我对不老泉没半点兴趣
so, if your heart is set,
所以  如果你决心已定
you may drop me off anywhere you like.
可以随便把我扔在哪
That'll be all, Quartermaster.
可以了  舵手
Your words surround you like fog and make you hard to see.
你的花言巧语让人很难看清你的真面目
And what of you, the mighty Blackbeard?
那你呢  了不起的黑胡子
Beheaded they say. Still, your body swam
他们说你被砍了头  但是身体
three times around your ship, then climbed back onboard.
绕船游了三圈  又回到船上
And here you are, running scared.
而你现在  用恐惧震慑人心
- Scared. - To the Fountain.
-恐惧  -所以你要去不老泉
The Quartermaster sees things before they happen.
舵手可以预见未来
He has foreseen my death, and so the fates have spoken.
他预见了我的死亡  命运已经决定
The threads of destiny woven.
命运之网已经张开
You have a ridiculously high regard for fate, mate.
你对命运的关注太荒谬了  伙计
- And you? - Me?
-你呢  -我
I'm skeptical of predicting any future... which includes me.
我对所有预言都持怀疑态度  包括我的
It'd be foolish to battle fate,
和命运抗争是愚蠢的
but I'd be tempted to cheat it.
不过我想要愚弄它
I will reach the Fountain. You will lead me.
我会到达不老泉  而你会带我去
That knife will serve you no better than the mutiny you devised.
除了叛变  那把刀已经没更大用处了
Mutiny served me well.
叛变很成功
It gained me an audience with you.
给我赢得了谒见你的机会
Aye.
是的
To warn you.
来警告你
Regarding your first mate,
关于你的大副
who pretends to be persons she is not.
她谎报了自己的真实身份
Do tell.
继续说
She is not your daughter.
她不是你的女儿
You dare to speak thusly of my flesh and blood?
你怎么敢这么说我的血脉
Sir, the woman is consummate in the art of deception.
先生  这女人精通骗术
I know.
我知道
As I mostly unwittingly set her on her wicked path.
是我不小心将她送上了邪路
Though I cannot claim credit
当然也不能否认
for her existing abundance of natural talent.
她极有天分
Angelica. My beloved daughter,
安琪莉卡  我亲爱的女儿
the one true good thing I have done in this life,
我这辈子干的唯一一件好事
and you claim to be the one who corrupted her?
你却声称自己把她毁了
Sir, what she is is pure evil.
先生  她是纯粹的魔鬼
More to be feared than a wild beast.
比野兽还要可怕
Hungry wild beast with gnashing teeth.
咬牙切齿的饥饿野兽
Vengeful, hungry from hell, beast...
充满仇恨  地狱般饥渴  野兽...
- Father? - Sweetness!
-父亲  -宝贝
No need to hurt him, Father.
你不用伤害他  父亲
He will help us. Won't you, Jack?
他会帮我们  对吧  杰克
You see? Even now, she attends to your welfare,
你看  即使是现在  她也惦记着你
giving lie to the claims you make of her.
即使你在这编造谎言挑拨离间
You will lead us to the Fountain. Yes?
你会带我们去不老泉吧
Put another way.
换种说法
If I do not make it to the Fountain in time...
如果我不能按时到达不老泉
neither will you.
那你也别想活命
I'll have a wee look-see
我马上
at those charts straight away then, shall I?
去看一眼海图  行吗
Sir.
先生
- Aye? - Captain, sir,
-什么事  -船长
I am unhappy to report rumors, sir,
我很不情愿地向您汇报  长官
among the crew, as to our destination.
关于我们的目的地  船员之间有了谣言
Shut your trap and make way.
闭嘴  走开
- That's the way of it, then. - No disrespect, sir.
-我叫你走开  -没有不敬的意思  长官
What do the men fear? Say it. Speak the words.
他们怕什么  说出来  告诉我
Whitecap Bay.
白浪湾
Aye, Whitecap Bay.
好吧  白浪湾
And every worthless seaman fears the name,
没用的水手都害怕这个名字
and rightly so,
自然而然
though few know why or dare to ask.
但没人知道为什么  也没人敢问
Be the stories true?
传说是真的吗
Say what robs you of your staunch heart, Gibbs,
说说是什么让你这么心惊胆战  吉布斯
or forever leave it to the wider fields of fancy.
不然的话就别危言耸听
Mermaids, Captain.
美人鱼  船长
Aye. Mermaids.
对  美人鱼
Sea ghouls, devil fish, dreadful in hunger for flesh of man.
食尸鬼  魔鬼鱼  迫切渴望着人肉
Mermaid waters, that be our path.
美人鱼的地盘  是我们的必经之路
Cling to your soul, Gibbs,
坚守你的灵魂  吉布斯
as mermaids be given to take the rest...
因为美人鱼会将灵魂以外的东西
to the bone.
吃干抹净
Steady! Steady, men! Find your courage,
稳住  稳住  鼓起勇气
or be ready to purpose your fear!
不然就准备屈服于恐惧吧
Save yourselves!
快逃命吧
- Man overboard! - Nay! A deserter.
-有人落水了  -不  是个逃兵
- Come about. - Nay!
-改变航向  -不
Gentlemen, I shall not ask any more of any man than what
先生们  我不再问任何人
that man can deliver,
他能怎么样
but I do ask this: Are we not king's men?
我只想问  难道我们不是国王的子民吗
Aye.
是
- On the king's mission? - Aye.
-执行国王的任务  -是
I did not note any fear in
西班牙人经过我们的时候
the eyes of the Spanish as they passed us by.
在他们眼里可没有任何恐惧
- Are we not king's men? - Aye!
-难道我们不是国王的子民吗  -是
Aye! Hands all off, and bear away!
这就对了  坚守岗位  打起精神
Stave on ahead to Whitecap Bay!
一往无前  直奔白浪湾
Bear on, Whitecap Bay!
继续前进  白浪湾
Come.
过来
Little drink?
来点酒吗
Wine, music, candlelight.
美酒  音乐  烛光
I think we've traveled down this road before, Jack.
这场景似曾相识  杰克
Yes, we have.
是的
I remember it well.
我记得很清楚
Winding, twisting and turning, gyrating, writhing.
摇摆  舞动  旋转  缠绵
Incessant writhing.
无尽的缠绵
Do you recall Saint Dominique?
还记得圣多米尼克吗
La Martinique.
马提尼克岛
I tried to kill you in Saint Dominique.
我在圣多米尼克想杀你来着
Either or.
管他呢
Hardly appropriate for a first mate.
作为大副这太不合适了
Was I the first? I've often wondered.
我是第一个吗  我真好奇
You can be so charming when you want something, Jack.
你有所求的时候总是这么迷人  杰克
The trick is finding out what.
问题在于发现你想要什么
The truth, then, is it?
真相  对吧
Blackbeard has served his purpose.
黑胡子已经达到目的了
You and I can go to the Fountain together,
我们可以一起去不老泉
where we shall bathe one another in equal shares of fame
我们可以共同名扬四海
and other assorted debaucheries.
还可以花样百出  纵情享乐
And I'll tell you the ritual of the Fountain.
我告诉你怎样进行不老泉的仪式
Yes. The profane ritual.
对  渎神仪式
Can I trust you, Jack?
我能相信你吗  杰克
- I need you on my side. - Oh, my dearest Angelica.
-我需要你支持我  -最亲爱的安琪莉卡
You and I are as thick as thieves, love.
我们现在亲密无间  我的爱
Tell me the rules.
告诉我方法
Water from the Fountain of Youth.
不老泉的泉水
The shimmering tear of a mermaid.
美人鱼闪烁的眼泪
The silver chalices of Ponce de Leon.
庞塞・德莱昂的圣杯
With these items...
有了这些东西...
- Yes? - With these items,
-什么  -有了这些东西
you may take all the years of life from another, Jack.
你就能得到另一个人的所有寿命  杰克
You know what that means.
你知道这意味着什么
We cannot go alone, you and I.
我们不能自己去  你和我
The ritual requires a victim.
仪式需要一个祭品
- That is unfortunate. - Yes, it is.
-这太不幸了  -确实
I find my desire for the Fountain greatly lessened.
我发现自己不是很想去不老泉了
But there is something onboard you do want.
不过船上确实有你想要的东西
What about Blackbeard?
黑胡子发现怎么办
He's in the chart room. We'll have to be quick.
他在海图室里  我们得快点
He keeps each ship as a prize.
他把这些船当作战利品
You help me, and I promise you your pick.
你帮我  我就让你选一艘
Though I think I know the one you will choose.
不过我想我知道你会选哪艘
The Black Pearl in a bottle?
黑珍珠号在瓶子里
Why is the Black Pearl in a bottle?
为什么黑珍珠号会在瓶子里
He's even more annoying in miniature.
它缩小后更讨人厌
- Do we have a deal, Jack? - Angelica, I know you.
-成交吗  杰克  -安琪莉卡  我了解你
You are not going to steal the life of some innocent man.
你不会向无辜的人窃取生命
What about the one-legged man?
那个独腿男人怎么样
I need years, Jack.
我需要寿命  杰克
Not for me. For my father.
不是给我  是给我父亲
I am truly the daughter of Blackbeard.
我真是黑胡子的女儿
You've fallen for your own con, love.
你骗人骗得分不清现实了  亲爱的
No, he is my father.
不  他确实是我父亲
The lies I told you were not lies.
我对你说的谎言其实不是谎言
You lied to me by telling me the truth?
你用真相对我撒谎
- Yes. - That's very good.
-对  -真不错
- May I use that? - I'm sure you will, anyway.
-可以借用吗  -反正你总会用
Of course I will.
当然了
So, will you not give up this quest?
所以  你不会放弃是吧
I want a father, Jack. I haven't had one.
我想有个父亲  杰克  以前从没有过
Angelica, your father, Blackbeard...
安琪莉卡  你父亲  黑胡子
he is evil,
是个魔鬼
and he will kill you given the chance.
一旦有机会他就会杀了你
- He cannot be saved. - And who are you to set
-他已经没救了  -你凭什么
the limits on redemption?
决定谁能被救赎
You stole years of my life, Jack. You owe me.
你偷走了我的年华  杰克  你欠我的
And you are en route to getting yourself killed,
你这是要害死自己
and I am not inclined to stand by and watch.
我不会就这么袖手旁观
Whitecap Bay!
白浪湾
All hands on deck! Set to the longboats!
全员集合  放下大艇
Lay'em out flat!
把网展平
No tangles. Make'em look pretty for our dainty guests.
别弄乱  得为我们的贵宾弄得漂亮点
We're gonna need light. A lot of light.
我们需要光  很亮的光
Come!
过来
Smell that? Whale oil. Stuff burns like a miracle from God.
闻见了吗  鲸鱼油  烧起来像神迹
- Can you make it work? - Made by the English.
-能让它亮起来吗  -英国人造的
Let's not get our hopes up.
别抱太大希望
The old moon in the arms of the new one.
月亮才刚刚露出一牙
First of the summer.
夏季的第一弯新月
Perfect for hunting a mermaid's tear.
猎取美人鱼眼泪的完美时机
We're doomed. They be drawn to man-made light.
我们完了  她们会被人造光吸引过来
- Sharks? - Worse than sharks, boy.
-鲨鱼吗  -比鲨鱼还可怕  孩子
There'll be mermaids upon us within the hour,
一小时之内美人鱼就会到这来
you mark my words. And we're the bait.
记住我的话  我们是诱饵
I heard it said a kiss from a mermaid
听说美人鱼的吻
protects a sailor from drowning.
能保护水手不被淹死
Don't be a fool! Mermaids are all female, son,
别犯傻了孩子  美人鱼全是雌性
and lovely as a dream of heaven.
像梦中的天堂一样美丽
But when it comes time to churn butter, so to speak,
但当她们露出本性  据说
they snatch a sailor out of a boat
她们会把水手拖出船外
or off the deck of a ship, have their way,
或者拖下甲板  总之是这样
and then the sailors are pulled to bottom and drowned and eaten.
然后把他们拖到海底  淹死吃掉
Or, sometimes, the other way around.
或者有时候  正好相反
- Sing. - What?
-唱歌  -什么
They like to hear singing.
她们喜欢听人唱歌
My name is Maria
我叫玛莉亚
A merchant's daughter fair
我是商人的女儿
- Louder. - And I have left my parents
-大点声  -我离开双亲
And 3,000 pounds a year
每一年赚上三千英镑
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
There is nothing can console me
只有快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
能让我的心得到慰藉
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
There is nothing can console me
只有快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
能让我的心得到慰藉
Lord save me.
神啊  救救我吧
Man, look. Look there.
看  看那边
You'll scare her off!
你会吓到她
Aye, and good riddance!
那可真是谢天谢地
Can you talk?
你会说话吗
Yes.
会
You're beautiful.
你真漂亮
- Are you the one who sings? - Aye.
-是你唱的歌吗  -是
Are you my jolly sailor bold?
你是我快乐勇敢的水手吗
- Aye, that I be. - Scrum, comport yourself!
-是  我是  -史考姆  清醒点
Boys! There ain't much been given to me
大伙们  我短暂而悲惨的一生中
in my brief, miserable life, there's the truth in it.
从来没得到过什么  真的
But, by God, I'll have it said
但是  天哪  我现在得说
that Scrum had himself a kiss from a proper mermaid!
史考姆要得到一个真正的美人鱼之吻了
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
There is nothing can console me
只有快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
能让我的心得到慰藉
Come all ye pretty fair maids
来吧美丽的少女们
Whoever you may be
不论你是谁
Who love a jolly sailor bold
爱着那快乐勇敢
That ploughs the raging sea
征服惊涛骇浪的水手
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
There is nothing can console me
只有快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
能让我的心得到慰藉
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我的心被丘比特射中
I disdain all glittering gold
我对金子也不屑一顾
There is nothing can console me
只有快乐勇敢的水手
But my jolly sailor bold
能让我的心得到慰藉
Out upon it! It has begun!
都出来  开始了
Light'em up!
点起来
Muster your courage! Drive'em to shore!
鼓起勇气  把她们赶到岸边
Nets into the water! Quickly!
把网撒进水里  快
Retreat, all, to land! For your lives!
撤退  所有人上岸  保命要紧
Retreat, I say!
快撤退
Cowards! Back in the water!
胆小鬼  回水里去
There be no refuge on land! On my word!
岸上没地方给你们躲  我说到做到
come on!
来
We got one!
我们抓到一个
I'm in love!
我恋爱了
Check the wounded!
查看伤员
See if you can find one mermaid still alive!
看能不能找到还活着的美人鱼
Come, give a hand!
快来  搭把手
Well done, sailor.
干得漂亮  水手
Did everyone see that?
大家都看见了吗
Because I will not be doing it again.
下次我绝对不这么玩了
Back to the ship. We head for a protected cove. Now.
回船  驶向安全地带  快点
- Lord. Is that? - Mermaid.
-老天  这难道是...  -美人鱼
- Give up this madness now. - I cannot.
-放弃这疯狂任务吧  -不行
Ever walk on the beach,
你走在沙滩上的时候
look back and see your footsteps in the sand?
会不会回头看自己留下的脚印们
It's like that, except the footsteps lie before me.
就是这感觉  不过我的脚印们朝向前方
- Footstep, actually. - Whitecap Bay, sir.
-是脚印  没有"们"  -白浪湾  长官
We must hasten.
我们必须加快步伐
We travel by foot. Gibbs, I require a heading.
咱们用走的  吉布斯  需要有人带路
- But, sir, the men. - They be dead already.
-但是长官  我们的船员...  -他们已经死了
- They don't sound dead. - Oh, is that so?
-听起来还没死  -真的吗
Well, I hear nothing but seagulls nesting.
我只听到海鸥筑巢的声音而已
What is it that you hear, Mr. Groves?
你听见什么声音了  格洛夫斯先生
Seagulls... nesting.
海鸥...在筑巢
- Nothing more. - Heading, Gibbs?
-没有别的了  -领路  吉布斯
My God.
老天
Your head or my heading.
你不领头  我就领走你的头
I'll have me one or t'other, I don't care which.
任选其一  我无所谓
All hands, forward!
全体前进
- It's to you now, Sparrow. - Was that really necessary?
-该你上场了  史派罗  -这样真有必要吗
Best you not know the exact whereabouts of my ship.
你最好不要知道我的船的下落
- I be a cautious man. - So be I.
-我可是个谨慎的人  -我也是
What I want first...
但我最想知道的是
...is Ponce De Leon's ship.
庞塞・德莱昂的船在哪
Why is it we've got to bring her along?
我们为什么要带她一起走
Because tears don't keep. We need them fresh.
我们需要新鲜的眼泪
What is the ritual again?
这什么仪式来着
Water from the Fountain and a mermaid's tear?
泉中水和人鱼泪
And two silver chalices.
还有两只银圣杯
One cup with a tear, one without.
一杯有眼泪  一杯没有
So, one with a tear and water in both?
就是两杯都有水  一杯里有泪
Quite complicated, is it not?
还真够麻烦的  是吧
Both get water. One gets a tear.
两杯都有水  其中一杯有眼泪
The person who drinks the water with the tear
喝那杯带眼泪的人
gets all the years of life from the other.
能获得喝另一杯的人的所有寿命
How many years?
那是多少年
All the years that they have lived,
所有已生之年
and they could have lived, if fate had been kinder.
和剩下的未活之年  如果命运发慈悲的话
Clergyman.
牧师
On the off chance that this does not go well for me,
万一万一我遭遇啥不测
I would like it noted here and now
我想跟你说
that I am fully prepared to believe in whatever I must,
我愿意相信你那些有的没的
so that I may be welcomed into that place
让我也能进那个好地方
where all the goody-goodies get to go. Savvy?
就是那些虚伪的老好人去的地方  懂?
We have a word for that, Jack. You can convert.
我们有个术语  杰克  你可以皈依
I was thinking more of an as-needed basis.
我是想等到万不得已再说
Quartermaster!
舵手
- Aye? - She cannot breathe!
-怎么  -她不能呼吸了
- She has water. - She needs air!
-箱里有水  -她需要空气
- Open this. - She will escape.
-把盖子打开  -她会逃走
- You're killing her. - I support the missionary's position.
-你会杀了她  -我支持传教士
See?
看见了吗
Onward.
继续前进
Just as I thought. Not this way!
和我想的一样  此路不通
This is the way, isn't it?
应该朝这边走  不是吗
'Course it is, but we should go around to the east.
方向当然对  但是应该从东边绕过去
That would take us out of the path of the chalices.
那就不是去拿圣杯的路线了
- Well, then we'll circle back. - There is no time.
-我们可以绕回去  -没那么多时间
You're the one who insisted on bringing the bloody mermaid.
是你非要带着那美人鱼
- Well, the mutiny didn't help. - You walk like a girl.
-那你还组织叛变  -你走得还真像个娘们
- You would know. - Someone must go.
-你想见识见识  -必须有人过去
You mean split up?
你是说分头行动
You mean jump? This I cannot wait to see.
你是说有人跳下去吧  我也想看人跳下去
Sparrow will go. Find the ship, retrieve the chalices.
史派罗跳下去  找到船  拿回圣杯
Sparrow? What makes you think he will come back?
史派罗  你觉得他还会回来吗
Yes, what makes you think he will come back?
是啊  你觉得他还会回来吗
We cannot trust him, Father. I'll go.
我们不能相信他  爸爸  让我去
She'll go.
她说她去
How much farther to the Fountain?
离泉水还有多远
I'm running out of time.
我没有时间了
About a day's march north, following that river,
大概沿着河  朝北走一天
you'll get to a series of pools. Then you're close.
就会看到一堆水塘  那就快到了
You will go.
跳吧
I was sure it would come to this.
我就知道会变成这样
You know that feeling you get
你们知道站在高处时
sometimes when you're standing in a high place?
有时候会有那么一种
Sudden urge to jump?
特想往下跳的感觉吗
I don't have it.
我就没有这种感觉
I need those chalices.
我需要圣杯
Shoot. Save me the bother of the fall.
开枪吧  还省得我自己跳了
You will go. You will return...
你跳下去  然后来找我
...or I will kill her.
要不然  我就杀了她
You won't kill your own daughter.
你不会杀自己的女儿
Quartermaster, get me six more pistols,
舵手  再给我拿六把手枪
remove the shot from all but two,
卸了子弹  留两支枪里有子弹
but do not tell me which two.
别告诉我是哪两支
You get to choose, Mr. Sparrow.
该你选了  史派罗
No.
不对
- Yes. - You're sure?
-这个  -你确定
'Course I am.
当然确定
Again.
再来
Please, they're not even loaded.
拜托  根本就没子弹
If you're so keen on killing her,
你要是那么想杀了她
- why don't you just let her jump? - What?
-为啥不让她跳  -什么
If you jump and die,
如果你跳下去  跌死了
then she will have her chance.
就轮到她了
Again.
再来
...if I jump, will I survive?
如果我跳下去  有活得可能吗
The doll.
玩偶给我
- Yes, now you will survive. - This is nonsense! I'm going!
-这样你也许就死不了  -简直胡扯  我跳
Wet. Wet again.
湿了  又湿了
We go on. Due north to the Fountain.
继续出发  向北走
Well played, Father.
演得不错  父亲
You knew which guns were loaded, right?
您早就知道哪两把枪有子弹吧
Of course, my love.
当然  亲爱的
Be nice to have a map about now.
要是有地图就好了
Or a ship.
或者有艘船也行
Stop! Hold very still.
站住  不许动
Ye dare not let it touch your skin.
不能让它碰到你
What? What be wrong with an older man having a hobby?
怎么  上了年纪的人有点爱好不行吗
What are you stopping for, eh? Push on!
停下干什么  赶紧走
- Push on! - You can sleep when you're dead.
-赶紧走  -死了之后有你睡的
Push on!
赶紧走
Fortune continues to favor us.
幸运女神继续眷顾我们
The Santiago.
圣地亚哥
Famously captained by Ponce de Leon.
庞塞・德莱昂曾让它享誉一时
There's no one there.
没有围观群众
Right, then.
好吧
We must not stop.
不能停下
You will walk.
你得自己走
I cannot.
我不会走
Walk or die.
不走就得死
Put your arms around me.
环着我的脖子
- I do not ask for help. - But you need it.
-我没要你帮我  -但你需要我的帮助
- We're in a hurry, yes? - Do not fall behind.
-不是赶路吗  -别拖后腿
Hold here 'til I say!
在这休息一会
Such beauty.
你真美
Surely you're one of God's own creations,
你一定是上帝创造的
and not a descendant of those dark creatures
不是那些未能踏上诺亚方舟的
who found no refuge on the Ark.
黑暗而堕落生物的后代
Such beauty...
如此的美
...and yet deadly.
却又致命
- Deadly? No. - You attacked me.
-致命?  不  -你攻击了我
No. You are different.
不  你不同
Different?
不同吗
Are you not? You protect.
不是吗  你保护了我
Did you?
是吗
You pushed me down out of the way.
你把我推开了
- You see the Fountain? - No, but we are close.
-你看见不老泉了吗  -没有  但已经很近了
Bring the creature. Cover its head.
带上那生物  捂上她的头
She has a name!
她有名字
Pray tell.
请讲
She is Syrena.
她是塞蕾娜
Ponce de Leon.
庞塞・德莱昂
If 40 pirates dreamt 40 nights of treasure,
四十个海盗连着四十个晚上梦见的财宝
it would not match the contents of this room.
也赶不上这屋里的财宝
You.
是你
- You. - No...
-你  -不
-...you. - I was here first.
-你  -是我先来的
- You, why are you here? - Blackbeard sent me.
-你为什么来这  -黑胡子派我来的
- Why are you? - Silver chalices
-你呢  -银圣杯
- for my royal liege. - Oh, please.
-为我的陛下  -得了
Back, back! We have to balance it out!
后退  后退  我们必须保证船的平衡
The whole ship will slide!
这船会滑下去
Right, then.
那好吧
What if we each choose an item of approximately equal weight?
那要是我们各选一样差不多沉的东西呢
Put it back!
放回去
We touch nothing!
我们什么也不能动
What about that?
那个呢
The chalices.
圣杯
Oi! Why do you get to look first?
凭什么你先看
Fine, then.
那好吧
- Together. - Together.
-一起看  -一起看
Rocks.
石头
The Spanish.
那些西班牙佬
They're ahead of us, mate.
伙计  他们比我们早来一步
I shall have a look at that map. If it's what I fear...
我该看看那地图  要是我想的没错...
I wonder why they left this behind.
他们怎么会把这东西留下
Don't touch the map.
别碰那地图
They know the path,
他们知道了路线
but I can also see where they'll most likely make camp.
但我也知道他们最可能在哪驻营
Jack!
杰克
Gibbs, I was just on me way to break you out of jail.
吉布斯  我正要去监狱救你来着
You stole my map.
你偷了我的地图
Right. Best be started.
好了  行动
Mermaids.
美人鱼
Careful, these pools run deep.
小心  这些水塘很深
If she escapes, all is lost. Quartermaster.
如果她逃了  就全完了  舵手
Look. Look!
看  看好了
Staked out to die, to dry in the sun.
她被系在桩上  在太阳下暴晒
Only half in the water. Not enough to live,
身体一半在水中  不够活命
but just enough to make the dying slow.
只能慢慢死去
Think on it.
考虑一下吧
Your people, murdered, harvested for their tears.
你的族群被杀害  只是为了眼泪
Syrena, won't you cry?
塞蕾娜  你难道不想哭吗
All die, even you.
你也难逃一死
- Soon, I hear. - Listen...
-快了  -听着
Listen.
听好了
Can you not hear your sisters scream?
你难道听不到你姐妹们的呼喊
Do you not hear them?
听不到吗
We need but one tear.
我们只需要一滴眼泪
Vile creature!
下贱的生物
- Chop off her fingers, one by one! - Choke her!
-一根根切掉她的手指  -掐死她
Cut out the tears from behind the eyes!
从眼睛底下挖出眼泪来
Where's your voice in this?
你看得下去吗
Maybe she'll have a change of heart when the sun rises.
也许日出后她就转变心意了
Oh, aye, she will burn, but I cannot wait for the sun.
对  她会灼伤  但我等不到日出
Perhaps we should build a fire.
也许我们应该生把火
- No. - Do not contest me, cleric.
-不行  -不准质疑我  教士
- You will not torture her. - We need only one tear.
-你们不准折磨她  -我们只需要一滴眼泪
I will tear every scale from her body one by one if I see fit.
可以的话  我会把她的鳞一片一片剥下来
If that displeases you, go pray.
要是你不满意  祈祷去吧
I was wrong. Not every soul can be saved. Yours cannot.
我错了  并不是所有灵魂都能拯救  你无药可救
Behold, gentlemen, a man formerly of faith.
看啊  各位  曾经有信仰的人
That vile creature, as you call her, is worth a hundred of you.
你说她是卑贱的生物  但你还赶不上她万分之一
Oh, you care for her?
哟  你关心她
You fancy her.
你爱她
And do not deny what is clear to my eyes.
我看得一清二楚  别否认这份感情
Question is...
问题是
...does she fancy you?
她爱不爱你
My God, she does. We are in luck!
老天爷  她还真爱你  走运了
Bring forth a tear...
流下一滴眼泪
...or witness the death of this poor soul.
或见证这可怜生命的消亡
Syrena, if you could manage a tear,
塞蕾娜  如果你能流下一滴眼泪
I would be grateful.
我将万分感激
Sadness, yes,
悲伤  是有
- but no sorrow... yet. - Not by your hand, Father!
-但却并不悲痛  -别脏了您的手  父亲
Time and tide wait for none. Quartermaster.
时间不等人  舵手
Aye, mermaids are tough.
美人鱼还真难搞
The lot of them.
都够难搞的
Tie her up like the others. And get rid of this.
把她绑起来  把这尸体处理了
- You are confident? - Yes.
-你有信心吗  -有
I am a woman. So is she.
我是女人  她也是
What's your play, Jack? Throwing in with Barbossa.
你这是演的哪一出  杰克  和巴博萨搭起伙来了
There is a girl...
有个姑娘...
...A female... of the opposite sex.
...一个女性...异性
- When is there not? - Perhaps I should say "Damsel."
-姑娘不是异性是什么  -也许应该说是少女
- You're rescuing a damsel? - Well, there's a first.
-你还救少女吗  -万事总有第一次
Yes, but it's just that I may have caused said damsel
但有可能我让这个所谓的少女
- some manner of harm many moons ago. - Out with it.
-几个月前受伤了  -不奇怪
Gibbs, this is the woman from Seville.
吉布斯  她是个塞维利亚的女人
Ah, you pretended to love her,
你装作喜欢她
then you left her and broke her heart.
结果你离开她  伤了她的心
Worse. I may have had, briefly, mind you...
比这更糟  我也许是  简短地说  就是
- ...stirrings. - Stirrings?
-造成了她内心波动  -波动
- Stirrings. - What? Like feelings, you mean?
-波动  -什么  就是有感情了吧
No, no, no. Not quite all the way to feelings. More like...
不不不  不是那个意思  更像是...
All right, feelings, damn you.
好吧  就是感情  该死的
And you left her still. That's low.
结果你还是离开了她  够低级的
Thank you.
谢谢
Stealth over force.
秘密行动
I'll take it from here on account of your condition.
接下来我搞定好了  你不太方便
You don't have termites, do you?
你没招白蚁吧
I appreciate your concern, Jack,
感谢你的关心  杰克
but I'll be keeping you company all the same.
但我还是会盯着你
Hold here, Lieutenant Commander. Wait for my signal.
在这等着  大副  等我指示
There. That one. That be the leader.
那边那个  就是头领
Make note of his tent because that's where...
记住他的帐篷  那就是...
No, wait. My God, that must be them right there.
等等  老天  那肯定就是圣杯了
Your sword smells funny.
你的剑闻起来很搞笑
Aye. Poison from the innards of poisonous toads.
是  我涂了蟾蜍内脏的毒
Just a scratch, you're a dead man in minutes.
蹭一下  几分钟内你就死了
Would you mind pointing it the other way?
你能不能别用剑指着我
I don't like toads.
我不喜欢蟾蜍
- What are you doing? - Planning an escape route.
-你在干嘛  -计划逃生路线
- Isn't that how you do it? - Yes.
-你不也这样计划吗  -当然
Or sometimes I just... improvise.
不过有时候我只是...即兴发挥
Now what?
现在怎么办
We stroll out, slow and steady.
咱们逛出去  慢而坚定
Just like we belong.
理所应当一样
- I'm sorry, Syrena. - Philip, you're alive.
-抱歉  塞蕾娜  -菲利普  你还活着
- Yes. - You came for me.
-是  -你来救我吗
Why?
为什么
You're different, are you not?
你是不同的吧
Do you know not of kindness? Compassion?
你善良  有同情心  是吧
Tears of sorrow, never.
悲痛才不会让它们落泪
Mermaids be too tough for that.
美人鱼太坚强了
But tears of joy...
但喜悦的眼泪
They say these be the more potent anyway.
都说这更有效
Syrena, on my word, I had no part in this.
塞蕾娜  我发誓  我并不知情
Let her go. You don't need her now.
放她走吧  你现在不需要她了
Let her go? No.
放她走  没门
Secure her bonds. We leave her with her own.
把她捆好  让她自生自灭
How's that escape route working?
想出什么逃跑方案了吗
Here's your chance to improvise.
展示你随机应变的时刻到了
I'm attempting it.
我在想呢
I might be able to get a hand loose.
大概我能松出一只手
Oh, you got a knife. That's very good.
你带着刀呢  非常好
Better.
比刀还好
I want one of those.
我也要喝
Here's to revenge. Sweet and clear.
复仇真是甜美甘洌啊
- Revenge? - Come, come, Hector.
-什么复仇  -得了吧  赫克托
If you wanted the chalices,
你如果想要那圣杯
you'd seen they were missing and gone.
你会眼睁睁看着它落入他人囊中吗
You were lying in wait, for Blackbeard.
你在伺机候着黑胡子
King George. Privateer. Wig.
乔治国王  私掠船  假发
Cheap theatrical facade.
这些伎俩太低级了
- I'm not buying it. - You weren't there that night.
-我才不信呢  -那晚你没在
When the Pearl was lost?
黑珍珠沉没的时候吗
Taken, not lost.
不是沉没  是被夺走了
We were off the coast of Hispaniola when we came under attack.
我们刚从伊斯岛起航就遭到了袭击
No provocation nor warning nor offer of parley.
没有征兆  没有警告  也没有谈判
We were peppered with cannon fire.
上来就是连天的炮火
And then the sea beneath the Pearl began to roil.
随后  海面翻滚起来
The Pearl was pitching and yawing violently.
黑珍珠开始剧烈晃动
Every plank, every rail,
每块甲板  每道栏杆
every spar, all at once, began to creak.
每根船杆全都开始吱嘎作响
The rigging had come to life.
帆缆也好像有了生命
Our own ship turned against us...
我们的船叛变了
...tangling the crew, wrapping around 'em like snakes.
缆绳就像毒蛇一样缠住船员
And wrapping around me leg.
缠住我的腿
But me arms were free and me sword was to hand.
但我的胳膊还能动  剑也还在手里
I am the master of me ship, not Blackbeard.
我才是这船的主人  不是黑胡子
I am the master of my fate, not Blackbeard.
我才是自己命运的主人  不是黑胡子
So I did what needed done.
所以我就采取了必要措施
I survived.
我活了下来
So... you're not after the Fountain.
也就是说  你不是要找不老泉
I care not for King George or tavern yarns
我才不在乎国王的命令
that give hope for a healed limb.
还是传闻说能治愈这瘸腿
But I'd give my left arm for a chance at Blackbeard.
但要是能干掉黑胡子  叫我牺牲左臂也情愿
- Not your right? - I need me good arm
-干嘛不是右臂  -右臂要留着
to drive my poisoned blade through his heart.
挥舞毒剑  刺穿他的心脏
I'll see you get the chance, mate.
看来你的机会来了  伙计
The prisoner's escaping.
犯人逃跑了
He's escaping! Fan out! Find him!
他逃了  扇形散开  抓住他
Go! Go!
快跑
Hold your fire! I want him alive!
别开枪  我要抓活的
I figured that was the signal.
我想那是信号
- Go! Prepare to move out! - The enemy is soon upon us.
-准备撤离  -敌人很快就追来了
I'm sorry about the chalices,
圣杯的事我很遗憾
Jack, but I've an appointment to keep.
杰克  但我还得赴个约
- I'll not be going back. - No need.
-我不会回去  -不用
- Shall we have a drink? - We'll drink at the Fountain.
-喝一杯怎么样  -到了不老泉再喝
How is it we can never meet without you pointing something at me?
我们每次见面你都要冲我舞刀弄剑吗
You brought the chalices, Sparrow?
圣杯带来了吗  史派罗
Aye. Oi!
当然
- I see you brought a friend. - I did.
-你还带了个朋友  -是的
And the one-legged man, he is near. Aye?
那个独腿海盗也在附近吧
Aye.
是的
Now...
现在
Before I go just handing them over,
在我交出它们之前
I do have one or two conditions.
我有那么一两个要求
- Name them. - Firstly,
-快说  -首先
I'll be having me compass back. No, no, that's secondly.
我想要回指南针  不不  那是第二个
Firstly, upon your word,
第一  你要答应
you will bring no harm to Angelica.
绝不会伤害安琪莉卡
I'll make no vows to the likes of you, Sparrow.
我不会对你这种人保证什么  史派罗
But it costs me nothing to admit
但也不妨承认
that she was never in harm's way.
她永远不会受到伤害
Secondly then, priorly firstly,
那么第二条  就是之前的第一条
I will be having me compass back.
把指南针还我
Please? I do deserve it.
拜托了  这是我应得的
Do you have any idea how
你知不知道
difficult it was to catch that filthy pig?
抓住这头臭猪有多费劲
Not the big one, the four-legged one.
不是大的那头  是四条腿的那头
Thank you. And thirdly, Mr. Beard,
谢谢  第三条  胡子先生
there are times, not very often,
有的时候  偶尔
when I do reflect upon my heinous misdeeds.
我会回想起自己卑劣的所作所为
Chief among them, I note how poorly I have treated Mr. Gibbs,
尤其是我对吉布斯先生的做法
- my loyal first mate. - Aye! Now you bring it up...
-我那忠心的大副  -现在你才说...
Left him to rot in jail, I did. Didn't care.
那会我任由他在监狱受罪  毫不关心
Still don't. But, point being, you must let him go free.
现在我也不关心  但问题是你得放他走
- Is that it? - I think so.
-就这样吗  -我想是的
Quick, or the pig runs, and good luck getting those chalices.
快决定  否则猪跑了看你怎么拿回杯子
Jack, if it's all the same to you, I'd be just as...
杰克  如果你不在乎这杯子  那我情愿...
Done.
成交
Release the swine.
放开那猪吧
Perhaps, if you don't mind,
如果你不介意
I could tag along with you folk for a...
我或许可以跟你们一起...
This will lead you to freedom, mate.
这能带你走向自由  伙计
I could have swore it was somewhere right around here.
我发誓就在这附近
We must not stop.
我们不能停下
Dead end.
死路
Dead. End.
死路  结束了
Jack, I'm starting to think you don't know where you're going.
杰克  你知不知道要怎么走
It is not the destination so much as the journey, they say.
人们说  沿途风景要胜过目的地
Chalices, if you please.
请把圣杯给我
Stand back.
退后
Jack...
杰克
...have you ever, in fact...
你到底有没有
...seen with your own eyes... the Fountain of Youth?
亲眼见过不老泉
I'm sorry, could you repeat the question, please?
抱歉  你说什么来着
Quartermaster.
舵手
No, no!
不不
Wait, wait! Wait.
等等
"Aqua... de Vida."
生命...之水[西班牙语]
Master Scrum...
史考姆先生
- ...do you mind? - Squire?
-如果你不介意  -拿着这个吗
So beautiful.
真美
Sparrow, I'll be the first to taste those waters.
史派罗  我要第一个喝那泉水
Father.
父亲
The one-legged man.
独腿海盗
- You brought him here. - Would I do that?
-你把他引来这里  -我会那么做吗
Edward Teach!
爱德华・提奇
For crimes committed on the high seas,
鉴于你在公海犯下的种种罪行
by the authority granted me by His Majesty the King...
国王陛下赋予我职权
...and with a goodly amount of personal satisfaction...
同时我个人也相当乐意
...I hereby place you in the custody of the court,
拘押逮捕你
and declare you to be my prisoner.
你是我的阶下囚
My trick's out, is that it?
我气数已尽了吧
Such crimes do include, but are not limited to, piracy, treason,
罪名包括但不限于  海盗行为  通奸叛国
murder, torture of the most heinous sort,
蓄意谋杀以及残酷折磨
including the brutal theft of one used, twisted, hairy right leg.
包括野蛮夺走一条饱经风霜的右腿
You... dare face this sword?
你不怕面对这把剑吗
This far away from your ship? Aye.
这里又不是你的船  当然不怕
Aye. That be the cold breath of fate I feel down my nape.
我能感到后背吹来冰冷的命运之息
But I'll have one last fight, by God.
但老天作证  我要打这最后一战
Kill 'em all!
杀光他们
Hang on a minute.
等一下
I just... I just need to understand something.
我只想弄清一件事
Right, so, you will fight against them,
你们要打他们
they will fight against you.
他们又要打你们
All on account of him wanting to kill him?
而这只是因为他想要杀他
Where is the sense?
这是什么逻辑
Exactly.
对吧
I say, let them fight each other while we lay back,
要我说不如让他们自己去打
watch, have a drink, place some wagers!
我们退后观战  喝喝酒赌赌钱
Aye.
好
- Kill 'em! - No quarter!
-杀掉他们  -不要怜悯敌人
Get off me!
滚开
Scrum, the chalices!
史考姆  圣杯
And the tear! Follow!
带上眼泪  跟我来
Fight!
打啊
Hand it over. The tear. There's a good lad.
交出眼泪来  好孩子
I'm more afraid of her than I am of you.
我更怕她一些
Hand it over. There's a good lad.
交出来  好孩子
- The chalices, if you please. - Sorry, Jack.
-把圣杯给我  -抱歉  杰克
I told you, I need years. And now, yours will do.
我说过我需要寿命  看来用你的就行
Scrum!
史考姆
Syrena...
塞蕾娜
Oh God, you will not take her.
主啊  不要带走她
If you have taken her, you will give her back.
如果你带走了她  还她回来吧
Give her back...
还她回来
Give her back, please. Please.
还她回来  求你了
I expected fate to put up more of a fight, eh?
我还期待命运给我安排个硬角色呢
I will not have that smile on your face as I strike you down.
你被我打到在地  有什么好高兴的
Take a gander, Edward Teach.
回头看看吧  爱德华・提奇
This land is hereby forever claimed in the glorious name
吾兹宣布  这片土地归伟大的
of His Majesty King George...
乔治国王陛下所有...
Someone make a note of that man's bravery.
找人记录下那人的英勇行为
Senorita, the chalices, por favor.
小姐  请把圣杯交出来
Only God can grant eternal life,
只有上帝才能赋予人永生
not this pagan water.
而不是这邪恶的泉水
Men, destroy this profane temple!
士兵们  毁掉这亵渎神圣的寺庙
The Fountain!
不老泉
You are a fool.
你这个蠢货
You seek in this place what only faith can provide.
你在这追寻的东西  只有信仰才能提供
Faith? In faith, there is light enough to see
信仰?  确实有照亮世界的光明
but darkness enough to blind.
但也有吞噬万物的黑暗
What devilry is this?
这是在搞什么鬼
- For the Pearl. - What have you done?
-为了黑珍珠号  -你做了什么
Angelica! Don't! It's poison!
安琪莉卡  别碰  有毒
I'm not such the fool to take on Blackbeard
不用一点恶毒的伎俩
without a little venomous advantage.
就想对付黑胡子  我还没这么天真
Jack!
杰克
I claim Blackbeard's ship and crew,
黑胡子的船和船员归我所有
and this sword, payment for my missing limb!
还有这把剑  以此补偿我失去的右腿
Hang on! Pull!
抓紧  用力拉
Do not waste my tear.
别浪费我的眼泪
Drink this. This one has the tear.
喝了这个  这杯里有眼泪
- You must drink the other. - No!
-你得喝另一杯  -不
I cannot save you both. One of you must sacrifice.
你们只有一个能活  另一个必须牺牲
You take it, Father, for your soul.
喝了它  父亲  拯救你的灵魂
Captain Teach, she's dying. You must save your daughter.
提奇船长  她快死了  你得救你的女儿
This one takes life?
这一杯是夺走生命的吗
This one has the tear and gives life?
这一杯有眼泪能赋予生命
Aye, hurry!
对  快喝
Angelica... Save me, my child.
安琪莉卡  救我  孩子
No.
不
I love you, Father.
我爱你  父亲
Wait a minute.
等等
In fact, it might have been the other way around.
事实上  好像弄反了
This cup had the tear, that one had the other bit.
这一杯有眼泪  那一杯没有
Trickster!
骗子
- Devil! - Father!
-恶魔  -父亲
You bastard! How could you?
你这混蛋  你怎么敢
Your father saved you.
你父亲救了你
Perhaps his soul is now redeemed, eh?
或许他的灵魂现在得到了救赎
You are hurt.
你受伤了
In body only.
只是身体受伤
My mind is at peace... because of you.
我的心灵很平静...因为你
- Me? - Yes.
-我  -对
I was lost.
我曾迷失了自己
The wind, the tides...
那狂风大浪
...they ought to renew a man's faith.
应该能改变一个人的信仰
But for me, only you.
但对我而言  只有你能
Philip, I can save you.
菲利普  我可以救你
You need only ask.
你只需开口请求我
- I seek but one thing. - What is that?
-我只求你一件事  -什么
Forgiveness.
宽恕
If not for me, you would never have been captured.
如果不是我  你就不会被抓
Ask.
开口吧
Forgive me?
宽恕我
I hate you.
我恨你
The bloke who saved your life?
恨那个救了你的人吗
The years I possess, stolen from my own father!
我的生命是从我父亲那偷来的
I only helped Blackbeard do what any father should have done.
我只是帮黑胡子尽了父亲的责任
You are cruel and ignorant.
你个冷血自大的混蛋
One pistol, one shot.
一把手枪  一枚子弹
To kill myself before I starve?
好让我在饿死前饮弹自尽吗
There's no trusting you, love.
我可不信你会这么做  宝贝
Besides, this is a well-traveled trade route.
再说了  这里船只来往频繁
You can signal a passing ship.
你可以向它们发送求救信号
Or you can just bite the proverbial bullet, as it were.
或者像俗语说的那样啃啃子弹
And how will I get free of these bonds?
我怎么才能弄开这些绳子
You broke free of your bonds half an hour ago,
半小时前你就挣开了
waiting for the precise moment to pounce.
等待袭击的最佳时刻
Admit it, Jack.
承认吧  杰克
- You still love me. - If you had a sister and a dog,
-你还爱着我  -如果你有个妹妹和一条狗
I'd choose the dog.
我会选择狗
Treasure! There is a chest with jewels!
宝藏  有个装满珠宝的箱子
Jewels with the power to rule the wind and tide!
拥有征服风浪力量的珠宝
- You're making that up! - Wait...
-你编的吧  -等等
I am with child. Yours.
我有身孕了  你的
I don't recall that we ever had...
我不记得我们有过...
- You were drunk! - I've actually never been that drunk.
-你当时醉了  -我从没醉到那种程度
Wait!
等等
There is something I want to say to you.
我有件事要告诉你
Something I wanted to say from the moment we first met.
我们第一次相见时我就想说了
Go on, then.
那就说吧
I love you.
我爱你
As do I.
我也是
Always have. Always will.
以前爱  今后也爱
I gotta go.
我得走了
Jack!
杰克
This is not over!
这事没完
Missed!
没打中
The Revenge is mine.
复仇号是我的了[同时意为复了仇]
Sir...
先生
We found this below decks.
我们在甲板下发现了这个
All hands! Ply to windward!
全员  开往上风向
Get cracking, ye blooming cockroaches!
动起来  你们这群蟑螂
The Crown served me well.
国王是对我不错
But now, by the gods of sea and sky...
但如今  大海蓝天诸神在上
...make way for Tortuga!
向托尔图加岛开进吧
Gibbs, you filthy, besotted shellback, you made it!
吉布斯  你这肮脏糊涂的老东西居然成功了
Aye!
是的
And I trust we managed a profit
我相信在这次的联盟中
- from our joint enterprise? - Feast your eyes.
-我们有所获利  -请大饱眼福吧
The compass led me straight and true.
指南针直接领我找到了它
What of Blackbeard's men guarding the ship?
你怎么对付黑胡子船上的看守
I employed the selfsame maneuver we perfected in New Guinea.
我用了在新几内亚大获成功的那个办法
Seemed a shame to leave an entire fleet behind.
如果留下一整只舰队不拿就太可惜了
Shame indeed.
确实可惜
I hate that monkey.
我恨那只猴子
So, the Pearl... Any idea how to get her out?
黑珍珠号要怎么弄出来
We shall need a crossbow, an hourglass, three goats.
我们需要一把弩  一个沙漏  三只山羊
One of us must learn to play
我们中的一个
the trumpet whilst the other one goes like this...
得学会吹小号  另一个得这样
- I know a man with a goat. - Good. I can go like this.
-我认识个人有山羊  -很好  那我可以这样
Jack, I have to ask...
杰克  我想问问
You had the chalices, the water, the tear...
你有了圣杯  泉水还有眼泪
You could have lived maybe forever.
你大概能长命百岁
The Fountain does test you, Gibbs.
不老泉会考验你  吉布斯
But better to not know which moment may be your last.
但最好还是别知道何时是生命的尽头
Every morsel of your entire being
在生命中的每个瞬间
alive to the infinite mystery of it all.
都能感受到生命本身无限的奥秘
And who's to say I won't live forever, eh?
再说  谁说我不会长命百岁
Discoverer of the Fountain of Youth.
不老泉的发现者
I have no say in it, Gibbs.
这事我说不了算  吉布斯
It's a pirate's life for me.
我注定是个海盗
Savvy?
懂了吗